Jesse Raso

UX Designer

Dynamic, personable, and focused computer science student with substantial knowledge and experience in providing technical guidance, and identifying opportunities in software development and information technology. Interested in human-computer interaction where I can explore and enhance my IT knowledge and skills such as user research, software development, programming logic, etc.

in linkedin.com/in/jessecraso

SKILLS

Java Figma CSS SQLite Javascript C/C++ Python HTML APIs Git Wordpress

Bootstrap

EDUCATION

BSc in Cognitive Science University of Toronto

09/2016 - 04/2023

- O Software Design.
- Software Tools & System Programming.

- Introduction to Computer Science.
- The Design of Interactive Computational Media.

ACADEMIC PROJECT

T-Card Android App (09/2021 - 12/2021)

- Developed an Android app that facilitates a virtual TCard to be used by students and faculty members at the University of Toronto.
- Created an interface for the UCheck menu that allows quick and easy access for users to complete the UCheck quiz and show their UCheck results.
- O Users are able to log in with information stored in the SQLite database.
- Incorporated features such as QR code reading, picture uploading and more.
- Created thorough test cases using knowledge of unit testing, integration testing, and mock objects to ensure each function in each class operated
 as per specifications.
- Communicated with team and applied acquired knowledge of object-oriented design and polymorphism to achieve a fully functional, expandable, and elegant design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Driver/Assembler

Home Installers

06/2018 - Present Toronto, ON

- Consistently deliver excellent customer service to demanding clientele, going beyond to fulfill their needs.
- Coordinate with the warehouse manager, the logistics coordinator, the owner, sales representatives, and fellow team members to maintain a professional and efficient workflow.
- Assemble products with care and aptitude, considering the client's personal home space, time limitations, and quality of the finished product.
- Picking and receiving orders at a warehouse, safely and ably driving a large van, sometimes in narrow downtown alleys or high traffic areas.



Food Server

Bar Reyna

07/2017 - 08/2018 Toronto, ON

- Relayed orders to the cooks and ensured that all orders were delivered on time and ensured the accuracy and quantity of every
- Provided customers with checks and took payments, attempted to up-sell food and beverages.
- Reliable support for bartenders; mixed cocktails, poured draft beer, provided bottle service, and made hot beverages including coffee, cappuccinos, espresso, and lattes.
- Assisted guests as needed during the dining experience to support servers and bartenders.
- Managed food expedition by making sure guests received their food and ensured quality control.
- Provided menus and suggested menu items, and daily specials in detail.

Key Holder

Pita Pit Canada

04/2015 - 08/2016 Niagara Falls, ON

- Supervisor duties included: cash management, product inventory, and staff management.
- Greeted and engaged with quests by building a rapport and noting their food preferences.
- Maintained teamwork to ensure that business always operated effectively and efficiently.
- Provided a hospitable customer experience by being personable and going beyond to fulfill customers' needs.
- Expedited and executed customer orders accurately and on a timely basis.

Concrete Foreman

Nick's Concrete

05/2013 - 04/2015 Niagara Falls, ON

- Led & supervised a crew by monitoring the completion of tasks and delegating resources accordingly.
- Prepared job sites and complete projects with deadlines.
- Worked efficiently in a physically demanding and challenging environment.
- Pour concrete, screed, and level flat surfaces.

Owner

Exushost.com

09/2010 - 08/2011

- Operated an online web hosting service and ensured proper maintenance.
- Took customer orders, inputted information into a database tracked orders and resolved customer issues.
- Managed customers' websites and emails.
- Answered incoming support calls and online ticket requests from web hosting customers.
- Maintained cloud webhosting management system.
- Oconfigured general networking (firewalls, subnets, routing, etc.).
- Created a backup system of all relevant files/documents in the event of a computer crash.
- Provided off-hours coverage and emergency support as needed.

Niagara Falls, ON